DamianoFossa

Software Developer



Contact +39 348 95 43 461 fossa.damiano@gmail.com LinkedIn: damianofossa Github: damianofossa

Skills

Python, JavaScript, React, Node.js, PHP, Wordpress, SQL, MongoDB, Business Model Canvas

Languages

Italian: mother tongue English: professional proficiency

Hobbies

Running, travels, coding, yoga

About me

I'm a web developer with experience in back-end and front-end development, with knowledge in various programming languages, frameworks, and libraries, such as Wordpress, React, and Node.js. With my passion for travels, I love immersing myself in new cultures and trying new things.

Experience

Sep 2017 - Present

Freelance Web Developer

Damiano Fossa – Europe based

I design and develop WordPress websites for entrepreneurs and organizations with a social mission. Some of the clients include WE Factory, SOOP: Stories on Our Plate, The Refugee Nation, EIT Digital Alumni

Apr 2018 - Present

Web Developer

EIT Digital Alumni Foundation - Remote

The EIT Digital Alumni Foundation is a network of students and alumni of EIT Digital, which organises meet-ups, maintains communities, keep track of alumni careers and support students and alumni to get in contact with companies, public institutions and academia. I am in charge of developing new features, updates, maintenance, and improving the UX of the website

- Drupal
- · HTML, CSS, Javascript

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017

Data Analyst Intern

Magyar Telekom – Budapest, Hungary

As part of my master thesis research titled "Data Analysis of Telekom Dataset - Change Point Detection", I worked with Telekom HU to investigate unusual behaviors in traffic in the Hungarian highways, such as traffic jams or car accidents. Telekom HU provided the dataset, which I analyzed by developing a method that detected the difference in the usual/average number of phones in a specific area where the event occurred.

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, Plotly)
- Bash

Feb 2015 - Dec 2015

Web Developer and Web Designer

Kemical S.n.c. - Vicenza, Italy

Back-end and front-end development of the food delivery app HappyEat; Web design of five Wordpress websites for small companies in the food and hospitality industry.

- Wordpress and PHP (Codelgniter)
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Dec 2014 - Jan 2015

Web Developer

IperMela Store S.r.l. - Vicenza, Italy

Back-end development and interface improvements of the Management Software for the Apple products shop, which handles orders, invoices, products inventory.

- PHP
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Mar 2014 - Jul 2014

Software Developer

KPro Consulting S.r.l. - Vicenza, Italy

Back-end development adding functionalities using Google Maps API to a Customer Relationship Management software (CRM).

- PHP
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Projects

2019 - Present What Women Say

Women Say is a library of hand-picked quotes by extraordinary women in the fields of science, tech, design, architecture, music, cinema, business, politics, and journalism. It aims to be a resource for thought leaders, keynote speakers, teachers, lecturers, writers and anyone who believe it's time to bring a broader and more equal set of voices 'on stage' and 'on paper'.

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017

Data Analysis of Telekom Dataset: Change Point Detection

As part of my master thesis research titled "Data Analysis of Telekom Dataset - Change Point Detection", I worked with Telekom HU to investigate unusual behaviors in traffic in the Hungarian highways, such as car accidents. Telekom HU provided the dataset, which I analyzed by developing a method that detected the difference in the usual/average number of phones in a specific area where the event occurred. The results were discussed in my master thesis presentation to the ELTE thesis jury of academics.

Feb 2017 - May 2017

SmartCar: For a delightful driving experience

Innovation and Entrepreneurship Thesis project about Self-Driving Cars. I developed a startup business idea offering real-time information about roads, such as traffic jams or car accidents to self-driving cars, through a system developed in the cloud.

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Backend and Business Developer

Business Development Lab project about JoinApp, an online platform specifically designed for Erasmus students to help them enjoy their free time with locals. I developed the backend and contributed to the business development of the App.

Education

2015 - 2017

Double Masters Degree in Software and Service Architectures of EIT Digital University of Trento, Italy - Eötvös Loránd University, Budapest, Hungary

2010 – 2014

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science

University of Trento, Italy